Guide to the Yevgeny Yevtushenko Papers M1088
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Yevgeny Aleksandrovich Yevtushenko papers
circa 1920-2006
bulk
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Yevtushenko, Yevgeny Aleksandrovich
M1088
88 Linear Feet (approx. 149 containers)
Items transferred to the Rare Book Division
Published books and periodicals have been transferred from the collection to the Rare Book Division where they are being individually cataloged and identified as part of this collection.
A complete list of these items follows:
published works from collection
Alcalay, Ammiel, The Cairo Notebooks, Singing Horse Press1993
Ball, Angela. Quartet. Carnegie Mellow University Press1995
Bashevis Singer, Isaac. Reaches of Heaven. Farrar-Straus-Giroux1980
Brutus, Dennis. Still the Sirens. Pennywhistle Press1993
Camner, Howard. Bed of Nails. Camelot Publishing Co.1995
Codrescu, Andrei. The Disappearance of the Outside. Addison-Wesley Publishing, Inc.1990
Collection of Works by and About Alexander Pushkin. Queens College1999
Cornillot, Francois. Le Nautonier de la Supreme Nostalgie. Editions Librarie du Globe1995
Dementiev, Andrei. Sneg v Ierusalime. Imprint-Golfarim1993
Dingman Watson, Nancy. Bluberries Lavender. Addison-Wesley1977
Dorfman, Ariel. La Muerte y la Doncella. Ollero & Ramos Editores1995
Ferguson, Marilyn. The Aquarian Conspiracy. J.P. Tarcher, Inc.1980
Flynn, Tony. Body Politic. Bloodaxe Books1992
Gertsman, Valentin l. Houston: Image and Imagination [exhibit catalog]1991
Havel, Vaclav. Open Letters. Faber & Faber1991
Hazo, Samuel. The Past Won't Stay Behind You. University of Arkansas Press1993
Higginbotham, Jay. Old Mobile. Museum of the City of Mobile1977
Iswolsky, Helene. No Time to Grieve. The Winchell Company1985
Keeney, Patricia. Selected Poems of Paricia Keeney, with introduction by Yevgeny Yevtushenko. Oberon Press 1996
Klemm, Barbara. Blick nach Osten. Fischer Verlag1995
Legge, Ludwig. Untermorgen Ubergestern. Truutvetter & Fischernacht 1979
Lodge, Kristen. Sword Become Words.
Lown, Bernard, M.D. The Lost Art of Healing. Ballantine Books1990
Nekhoroshev, Yuri. Yevgenii Yevtushenko: Bibliograficheskii Ukazat'el. Chelyabinskii Pedinstitut 1981
Ortiz Hill, Michael. Dreaming the End of the World. Spring Publication 1994
Oz, Amos. Panther in the Basement. Harcourt Brace and Company1998
Peonides, Panos. Eva Allo Oboiporiko. Lemesos1995
Phillips, Michael J. Selected Love Poems. Hackett Publishing Co.1980
Pollastri, Georgia. Ciclo. Grafiche Biesse1995
Porter, Dorothy. The Monkey's Mask. Hyland House1994
Pulco, Carlo. Pittura Poesia. Italo-Latino Americana Palma Editrice1991
Pusche, Alk. Die Evtusenko-Vertonungen von Dmitrij Sostakovic.
Rain Crowe, Thomas. The Personified Street. New Native Press1993
Rebolledo, Francisco. Rasero. Louisiana State University Press 1995
Saludos! Poemas de Nuevo Mexico. Pennywhistle Press1995
Schmidt-Macon, Klaus F. Aschenspur. Fotokunst-Verlag Groh1998
Schramm, Godehard. Grutz der Spatz als Papagei. Spatlese Verlag1985
Scott, Cyril. The Initiate. Samuel Weiser, Inc.1988
Stonov, Dmitri. In the Past Night. Texas Tech University Press1995
10 Anni di Poesia. Grafic House Editrice1995
Vetrov, Boris. Ulibaites', gospoda!. Liberty Publishing House, Inc. 1998
Yevtushenko, Yevgeny. Izbrannaya proza. Eksmo-press1998
Jewtuschenko, Jewgeni. Der Wolfspass. Verlag Volk und Welt2000
Zagato, Franco. Che ne sai, povero poeta? Pellicanolibri, 1992
CD The City of No and the City of Yes. Yevgeny Yevtushenko with Paul Winter Consort
CD So mnoyu vot chto proiskhodit. Nikitini, Tatyana i Sergei; lirics by Yevtushenko
CD So mnoyu vot chto proiskhodit. Nikitini, Tatyana i Sergei; lirics by Yevtushenko
Scope and Content
The Yevtushenko Papers include personal and professional papers of Russian poet Yevgeny Yevtushenko. Although not complete, the collection provides substantial material on Yevtushenko's personal and literary career, which cannot be separated from the political context of the time.
The papers were received in very little order. Where materials were identified and categorized by Yevtushenko, that arrangement has been preserved and expanded to include uncategorized portions of the collection. The collection consists of nine series: 1. Correspondence, 2. Political Papers, 3. Manuscripts, 4. Manuscripts by Others, 5. Performances and Exhibits, 6. Personal Papers, 7. Photographs, 8. Audiovisual Materials, and 9. Clippings. The collection also includes books by Yevtushenko and books from his library, many with inscriptions to Yevtushenko from the authors.
Names and titles have been transliterated according to the simplified American Library of Congress standard. Exceptions include those names for which a standard exists; for example, Yevtushenko is used rather than Evtushenko, and Yeltsin instead of El'tsyn.
Please note that some accessions may not be fully processed or described.
Biography
Yevgeny Aleksandrovich Yevtushenko was born on June 18, 1933 in Zima Junction, Siberia. His father, Aleksandr Gangnus, was a geologist who wrote poetry and taught Yevtushenko to love books. His mother, Zinaida Ermolayevna Yevtushenko, was a geologist and a singer. Both of Yevtushenko's grandfathers were victims of Stalin's purges in the late thirties.
After Yevtushenko's parents separated, he went to Moscow with his mother, whose surname he adopted. In the early years of World War II, Yevtushenko and many other children in Moscow were evacuated to Siberia. He returned to Moscow in 1944. After being expelled from school at the age of 15, Yevtushenko briefly joined his father on a geological expedition in Kazakhstan.
Yevtushenko's literary career took off in 1949 with the publication of his first poem in the journal Sovetskii Sport (Soviet Sport). His first book of poetry was published in 1952. He became the youngest member of the Soviet Writer's Union and was admitted to Moscow's Literary Institute, which was highly unusual for someone without a school certificate. However, he eventually left the Literary Institute without graduating.
Stalin's death in 1953 had a tremendous impact on Yevtushenko and his poetry. He witnessed the crowd that resulted in the trampling death of 150 mourners gathered in Moscow's Trubnaia Square. Yevtushenko's shock translated into disillusionment with Stalin and an appreciation for the importance of greater individual responsibility. His subsequent poetry was less conformist, largely anti-Stalinist, and blended public and private themes. Yevtushenko became the most visible of a generation of young, post-Stalinist poets that included Andrei Voznesenskii and Bella Akhmadulina. They revived the Russian tradition of popular poetry readings, attracting tens of thousands of fans to readings in sports stadiums and public squares.
In 1961 Yevtushenko wrote perhaps his best-known work, "Babii Iar." Babii Iar is a ravine in the suburbs of Kiev where tens of thousands of Russian Jews and others were slaughtered by the Nazis during World War II. In his poem Yevtushenko noted the absence of a monument to these victims of Nazism and attributed this fact to Russian anti-Semitism. The poem was immensely popular in the Soviet Union, and the Soviet composer Shostakovich developed his Thirteenth Symphony around it and other poems by Yevtushenko. Despite the popularity of "Babii Iar," Yevtushenko was not allowed to give a public reading of the poem in Ukraine until the 1980s.
Yevtushenko's favor with the Soviet government fluctuated. As a result of his defense of Dudintsev's critical novel Not by Bread Alone, Yevtushenko was expelled from the Literary Institute and the Communist Party's youth organization in 1957. He was reinstated under Khrushchev's thaw and given permission to travel and read his verse abroad, where he had gained wide acclaim. He gave poetry readings throughout Eastern and Western Europe, the United States, Cuba, Africa, and Australia. However, after Yevtushenko published his uncensored autobiography in France in 1963, the Soviet government curtailed his public readings and revoked his travel privileges until 1966.
Yevtushenko enjoyed mixed support among Soviet writers and dissidents. Many criticized him for collaborating with the state, largely because he managed to stay out of prison, psychiatric hospitals, and labor camps. However, on numerous occasions Yevtushenko defended fellow writers, including Solzhenitsyn.
In the seventies Yevtushenko ventured into other art forms. He produced a play entitled Pod kozhei statui svobody (Under the Skin of the Statue of Liberty) in 1972 and published his first novel, Iagodnye Mesta (Wild Berries), in 1981. He played the leading role in Savva Kulish's 1979 movie Vzlet (Takeoff). He also turned to photography, publishing three books of photographs and exhibiting his work around the world. Yevtushenko wrote and directed two films, Detskii Sad (Kindergarten) and Pokhorony Stalina (Stalin's Funeral).
With the coming of Gorbachev, Yevtushenko became a prominent spokesperson for glasnost. In 1988 he helped establish the Memorial Society with Sakharov to honor the victims of Stalinist repression. In 1989 he was elected to the Congress of People's Deputies in Kharkov, Ukraine. During the 1991 August coup, Yevtushenko joined Yeltsin in the defense of the White House, reciting his hastily written poem "August 19th."
Yevtushenko was elected an honorary member of the American Academy of Arts and Letters in 1987. He has published over 40 books of poetry and his work has been translated into 72 languages. Yevtushenko has been married to the poet Bella Akhmadulina, to literary translator Galina Semyonovna Sokol, with whom he has one son, and to British translator Jan Butler, with whom he has two sons. He currently lives with his fourth wife, Maria Novikova, and two youngest sons in Moscow and Oklahoma. Yevtushenko teaches at the University of Tulsa in Oklahoma and at Queens College in New York.
Note: this biographical sketch draws heavily on the biography of Yevtushenko published in the 1994 Current Biography Yearbook.
Provenance
Purchased, 1999-2011.
Russian poetry.; Russian literature -- 20th century; Winters, Paul; Yevtushenko, Yevgeny Aleksandrovich; Salisbury, Harrison; Tselkov, O.; Ginsberg, Allen; Todd, Albert; Shostakovich, Dmitriéi Dmitrie; Dutton, G.; Adamovich, G.
- Correspondence, Series 1.
  Scope and Contents note
  Personal and business correspondence. Prominent correspondents in the General Subseries include Georgii Adamovich, Isabel Allende, Lawrence Ferlinghetti, Allen Ginsberg, Graham Greene, Iurii Nekhoroshev, Pablo Neruda, Ancel Nunn, Octavio Paz, William Jay Smith, Oleg Tselkov, Harrison Salisbury, and Dimitry Shostakovich, as well as a number of lesser known Georgian and ethnic minority poets. Letters from Yevtushenko consist primarily of faxes regarding logistical details. Family correspondence includes letters to and from his four wives and five children during his many absences from home. Prominent correspondents in the Friends Subseries include Australian writer Geoffrey Dutton, Russian writer Aleksander Mezhirov, translator Albert C. Todd, and composer Paul Winter.
  - Subseries 1. General
    - Aa - Al, includes one photograph (Box 1, Folder 1)
      Handwritten letter from great Chuvashian poet, Gennady Aigi, 1991 July 22. Handwritten note from Chingiz Aitmatov. Correspondence to Yevtushenko from Meg Simonton of Albertson College, Marcia Franklin of Idaho Public Television, and the Log Cabin Literary Center concerning arrangements for his 1994 visit to Idaho. One typed letter from Margarita Aliger, poet and member of the Writer's Union, reviewing Yevtushenko's new poem "Fuku". Two-page handwritten letter from Isabel Allende, Chilean writer, concerning writers repressed under Pinochet.
      Log Cabin Literary Center; Simonton, Margaret D.; Aitmatov, Chingiz; Albertson College; Idaho Public Television; International Arts/Humanities Institute; Aigi, G.; American Association of Neurological Surgeons; Franklin, Marcia; Aliger, Margarita; Allende, Isabel
    - Adamovich, G., 1968 - 1971 (Box 1, Folder 2)
      Handwritten letter, 1 p., 1968 Apr. 5; Photocopy of handwritten letter, 3 p., n.d. Handwritten letter, 1 p., 1968 Aug. 30; Handwritten card, 1 p., 1971.
      Adamovich, G.
    - Am - Az (Box 1, Folder 3)
      Two-page typed and signed letter from Gonzalo Arango, Colombian poet and leader of the Nadista movement.
      Astaf'ev, Viktor; Avelino, Francisco; Arango, Gonzalo
    - Anfinogenov, Artem [writer] (Box 1, Folder 4)
      Anfinogenov, Artem
    - Askol'dov, A. (Box 1, Folder 5)
      Director of the film "Commissar".
    - Ba - Be (Box 1, Folder 6)
      One handwritten letter from Bulgarian poet Vladimir Bashev. Two notes from Garig Basmadjian concerning Yevtushenko's forward for a bilingual anthology of Armenian-American poets. Two-page handwritten letter from Leonard Bernstein concerning possible collaboration on the music for the Musketeers script.
      Yale University Press; Unicef; Berquist, Philip; Bernstein, Leonard; Bat, Luba; Basmadjian, Garig; Basheva, Vladimir; Baldini & Castoldi
    - Bf - Bo, Includes photographs (Box 1, Folder 7)
      One typed and signed letter from French poet and critic Alain Bosquet concerning translation of Yevtushenko's poems.
      White House; Böll, Heinrich; Boyars, Marion; Bosquet, Alain; Bogdanova, Natalia; Billington, James; Bikel, Theodore
    - Boys, Barry (Box 1, Folder 8)
      Boys, Barry
    - Bp - Bz (Box 1, Folder 9)
      One typed and signed letter from French poet and critic Alain Bosquet concerning translation of Yevtushenko's poems. One typed and signed letter from Zbigniew Brzezinski dated March 26, 1979 concerning the President's appreciation for an inscribed volume of Yevtushenko's poetry and regret for not being able to meet with him.
      Braggs, Earl S.; Brzezinski, Zbigniew; White House
    - Butorin, A. (Box 1, Folder 10)
      Butorin, A.N.; White House
    - Ca - Ck, Includes one photograph and a watercolor painting (Box 1, Folder 11)
      One handwritten note from Georgian author Amirejibi Chabua. One handwritten letter from Georgian poet Simon Chikovani. One handwritten letter from poet Boris Chichibabin.
      Chabua, Amirejibi; Cohen, Stephen; Consuegra, Hugo; Chichibabin, Boris; Cheever, John.; M & S The Canadian Publishers; Chikovani, Simon; Chiladze, Otar; Chiladze, Tamaz; Chinenkov, A.; British Committee for the Restitution of the Parthenon Marbles; Citizens Committe for Constitutional Liberties
    - Cl - Cz (Box 1, Folder 12)
      Cohen, Stephen; Consuegra, Hugo
    - Curman, Peter (Box 1, Folder 13)
      Curman, Peter
    - Da - De (Box 1, Folder 14)
      "Open Letter to Yevgeny Yevtushenko" from Vaagn Davtian in Yerevan.
      Davtian, Vaagn; Dalton, Catherine; New England Poetry Club; Dayan, Moshe; Da Capo Chamber Players
    - Davidson, Bill and Gracie (Box 1, Folder 15)
      Davidson, Bill; Davidson, Gracie
    - De Napoli, Francesco, Includes a soft cover book of 83 pages. (Box 2, Folder 1)
      Includes a small book by De Napoli "Attività Culturali nel Cassinate 1978/1995" which has a picture of Yevtushenko on the cover.
      De Napoli, Francesco
    - Df - Dz (Box 2, Folder 2)
      One letter signed and one copy of a letter from Kirk Douglas to Yevtushenko concerning "Musketeers". Three handwritten letters to Yevtushenko from Nancy (Nin) Dutton, first wife of Geoffrey Dutton. One handwritten letter with six-page typed review of Yevtushenko's poetry from Ossetian writer Naphi Jusoiti
      Doctorow, Edgar L.; Djusoiti (or Jusoiti), Naphi; Dutton, Nancy (Nin); Douglas, Kirk
    - Ea - Ez, Includes one photograph. (Box 2, Folder 3)
      One typed letter from Osborn Elliott, Editor and Chairman of the Board of Newsweek, concerning a new feature in the magazine in which he would like Yevtushenko to participate. One typed and signed letter from I.G. Ehrenburg, addressed "Dear Comrades," in which he declines to speak out for Yevtushenko, dated 1960 January 19. This letter was addressed to Z.E. Osilenker. Two handwritten letters, photograph, and business card from writer and editor Shlomo Even-Shoshan. Three handwritten letters from Svetlana Evstratova, actress who played the main role in "Detskii Sad."
      Europaverlag; Even-Shoshan, Shlomo; Emelianoff, André; Erenburg (Ehrenburg), I.G.; Elliott, Osborn; Ritz Paris Hemingway Award; Ellis, Royston; The Explorers Club; Evstratova, Svetlana; Elaine Kaufman Cultural Center; Newsweek
    - Emin, Gevorg (Box 2, Folder 4)
      Four handwritten letters and one telegram to Yevtushenko from the Armenian poet Gevorg Emin.
      Emin, Gevorg
    - Fa - Fz (Box 2, Folder 5)
      Eight-page typed letter to Yevtushenko in verse form in Slovak from "Great Slovakian Poet" Lubomir Feldek. A two-page typed and signed letter from Luis A. Ferré, El Gobernador del Estado Libre Asociado de Puerto Rico. Catalog of Frumgarts photo exhibit inscribed to Yevtushenko and signed, 1989 Jan 15.
      The Faulkner Society; University of Peace, Santa Fe, New Mexico; Filatov, Leonid; Frumgarts, Mikhail; Ferré, Luis A.; Feldek, Lubomir; Faulkner, Estelle O.; Fallaci, Oriana
    - Ferlinghetti, Lawrence (Box 2, Folder 6)
      Copy of poem "Populist Manifesto: for Poets, with Love" with initials dated, 1975 May. Two fragments of handwritten letters, n.d. A signed printed copy of "Adieu à Charlot: Second Populist Manifesto", 1979 March 19. Handwritten and signed letter, 1979, May 7. Fragment of typed letter with handwritten note and signature, 1979 June 10. Photocopy of handwritten letter to Yevtushenko and of Ferlinghetti's letter to the Eidtors of the Times, 1999 May 17. Photocopy of same. Typed letter signed by Ferlinghettie and Joan McIntyre to Yevtushenko concerning saving the whales, n.d.
      McIntyre, Joan; Ferlinghetti, Lawrence
    - Ga - Gl (Box 2, Folder 7)
      Handwritten note concerning Spanish poetic rhythms from Gabriel García Márquez, 1979.
      Gass, Boris; García Márquez, Gabriel; University of Cape Town; Tsigmond, Anna; Gluz, Mikhail Semenovich; Gewirtzman, Lillian; Gerdov, K.; Gawryszeski, Carol
    - Gedin, Per and Brigitte (Box 2, Folder 8)
      Gedin, Per; Gedin, Brigitte
    - Ginsberg, Allen (Box 2, Folder 9)
      One handwritten and signed note on letterhead from a hotel in Managua, 1982 Jan 24. Several handwritten postcards. One typed and signed letter to Yevtushenko concerning Victor Sosnora's trip to the United States, 1987 Sep 16. One handwritten "telephone message", 1988 Nov 16.
      Ginsberg, Allen
    - Gm - Gr (Box 2, Folder 10)
      Two typed and signed letters from British author Graham Greene.
      Greensboro Jewish Federation; Gordey, Beverly; Doubleday; Greene, Graham
    - Gs - Gz (Box 2, Folder 11)
      Letter to Yevtushenko from Margaret Guiteras, Assistant Treasurer of Chase Manhattan Bank, concerning meetings regarding film financing.
      Gutchin, Israel; Gudiashvili, Lado; Chase Manhattan Bank
    - Ha - Hz, Includes photographs. (Box 2, Folder 12)
      Two typed and signed letters and one card with pictures to Yevtushenko from Frank Hardy.
      The Macmillan Company of Australia; Simon Fraser University; Nordiska Strakosch Teaterforlaget; Jeremy Isaacs Productions, Ltd.; Hoagland, Guy; Henry, Roger; Hardy, Frank; Hansen, Hanne Wilhelm
    - Ia - Iz (Box 2, Folder 13)
      Handwritten postcard from Turkish writer Ozdemir Ince.
      Ince, Ozdemir; International Biographical Centre
    - Ipin, Pu (Box 2, Folder 14)
      Ipin, Pu
    - Ja - Jz (Box 3, Folder 1)
      Photocopy of a handwritten note from Mick Jaggar asking Yevtushenko to have the lyrics to "War Baby" translated into Russian, 1987 Aug 21.
      Bantam Books, Inc.; San Jose Mercury News; Jones, Holly; Jones, James; Jagger, Mick; Jodorovsky, Raquel
    - McVay, Gordon (Box 3, Folder 1)
      McVay, Gordon
    - Ka - Kl, Includes cards with photographs. (Box 3, Folder 2)
      Kendrick, Jack; Kline, George and Virginia; Kapranov, Gennadii
    - Karchin, Louis (Box 3, Folder 3)
      Several letters from Louis Karchin, American composer, to Yevtushenko concerning "American Visions", his song cycle based on two of Yevtushenko's poems.
      Karchin, Louis
    - Km - Ko (Box 3, Folder 4)
      Koller, Jay; Koporulina-Lisianskaia, Antoni; Marathon Pictures
    - Kp - Kz (Box 3, Folder 5)
      Kushner, A.; Krochik, Gennady; Vestnik Information Agency, Inc.
    - Kudimova, Marina (Box 3, Folder 6)
      Six handwritten letters to Yevtushenko from Marina Kudimova, Russian poet.
      Kudimova, Marina
    - La - Le (Box 3, Folder 7)
      Typed and signed letter from the great World War II Russian poet Konstantin Levin, 1 p., 1977 Dec. 7.
      Lagorio, Gina; Centre National de la Cinématographie; Lebedev, V.; Lang, Daniel; Levin, Konstantin; Leonovich, Vladimir; CaféTeatret; Levin, Mark
    - Lesnevskii, Stanislav (Box 3, Folder 8)
      Five handwritten letters and one telegram dated from 1973 - 1988.
      Lesnevskii, Stanislav
    - Lf - Lz, Includes one coin (Box 3, Folder 9)
      There is a sealed envelope which says "10p. given by Dr. Sid Lubert, first donation for Yevtushenko's film 'The End of the Musketeers'."
      Lin'kova, Vera; Lindhart and Ringhof; Los Angeles International Film Festival; Loseff, Lev; Raduga; López-Pacheco, Jesús
    - Mac - Mc (Box 3, Folder 10)
      One typed and signed letter from Larry McMurtry sending Yevtushenko some of his books, 1990 May 28; one two-page handwritten letter from Larry McMurtry explaining why he declined to join Yevtushenko's Lithuanian resolution.
      McMurtry, Larry
    - Ma, Includes a musical score (Box 3, Folder 12)
      A handwritten note with handwritten sheet music for Yevtushenko's poem "Dobrota", music by O. Mamaeva. One page typed and signed letter from Alberto Manjarré Wilches informing Yevtushenko of the death of Gonzalo Arango, 1976 Oct 15. Short handwritten note by Imelda Marcos on Office of the President of the Philippines letterhead, 1973 July. Invitation by Imelda Marcos to a dinner in honor of Yevtushenko, 1973 Jul 15. Short handwritten note from Kurt Masur and the New York Philharmonic.
      E.P. Dutton & Co. Inc. Publishers; Macrae, Elliott B.; Man, Gao; Manjarrés Wilches, Alberto; Marcos, Imelda; Marshall, Hubert; Masur, Kurt
    - Md - Mi (Box 3, Folder 13)
      Appalachian State University; Medina, Kate; Mekshen, Svetlana; Mixter, Perry
    - Mezhakoff-Koriakin, Igor (Box 4, Folder 1)
      Mezhakoff-Koriakin, Igor
    - Mj - Mz (Box 4, Folder 2)
      The Folio Society
    - Molina, Cesar Antonio (Box 4, Folder 3)
      Molina, Cesar Antonio; Circulo de Bellas Artes
    - Na - Nz, Includes a photograph. (Box 4, Folder 4)
      "Las Nuevas Arcas del Diluvio", a poem sent to Yevtushenko in both typed and handwritten form. A handwritten note from Pablo Neruda, and a copy of a poem Neruda wrote about Yevtushenko.
      Central Florida Film and Video Festival; Robson Books, Ltd.; Norton, Boyd; Nobrega, Nisia; Neruda, Pablo; Neizvestnyi, E.; Neff, Jason; Nashville Committee to Free Angela Davis; Nagibin, Yura
    - Nekhoroshev, Iurii (Box 4, Folder 5)
      Nekhoroshev, Iurii
    - Nekrasov, Viktor (and Yevtushenko's comments), 1975 Nov. 24 (Box 4, Folder 6)
      Handwritten letter, 4 p., 1975 Nov. 24. Also includes handwritten comments by Yevtushenko, 1 p.
      Nekrasov, Viktor
    - Nunn, Ancel and Reneta (1995 - 1997) (Box 4, Folder 7)
      Nunn, Renata; Nunn, Ancel
    - Nunn, Ancel and Reneta (1998 - 1999) (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Oa - Oz (Box 4, Folder 9)
      Typed letter and copy to Julian Bach dictated but not signed by Jacqueline Onassis, declining to publish "Don't Die Before Your Death" on behalf of Doubleday.
      Ognev, Vladimir; Onassis, Jacqueline; O'Donnell, John; O'hara Geare, Jill; Doubleday; Oz, Amos
    - Pa - Pi, Includes photographs. (Box 4, Folder 10)